Congratulations on reaching the end of the section.
-: Felicidades por llegar al final de la seccin.
Files is an extremely useful thing in Python
Files es una cosa extremadamente til en Python
and in any programming language.
y en cualquier lenguaje de programacin.
Not everybody uses databases yet,
No todo el mundo usa bases de datos
even though they are becoming more and more popular,
an, a pesar de que cada vez son ms
and often you'll want to share files with your users
populares, y con frecuencia querr compartir archivos con sus usuarios o
or with other stakeholders in your programme,
con otras partes interesadas en su programa, por lo
so it can be really useful to write things to a file.
que puede ser realmente til escribir cosas en un archivo.
Not only for saving the status of your programme,
No solo para guardar el estado de
but also to share information, maybe to send it
su programa, sino tambin para compartir informacin, tal
over the internet as we will look at later on,
vez para enviarlo a travs de Internet, como
and to do a number of other things.
veremos ms adelante, y para hacer otras cosas.
Files are very important for that reason,
Los archivos son muy importantes por esa razn,
so hopefully now you are more comfortable
as que espero que ahora est
in writing files with Python.
ms cmodo escribiendo archivos con Python.
In addition, often we want to read from files
Adems, a menudo queremos leer de los archivos para
to extract data,
extraer datos, para comprender lo
to understand what other programmes are giving us,
que otros programas nos estn dando, as que
so I hope you are confident doing that now as well.
espero que tambin se sienta seguro de hacerlo ahora.
If you have any problems, of course,
Si tiene algn problema, por supuesto,
please ask in the course Q and A,
pregunte en el curso Q y
and we'll be more than happy to help.
A, y estaremos encantados de ayudarle.
With that said, let's move over to the next section.
Dicho esto, pasemos a la siguiente seccin.
I'll see you there.
Te ver all.